- [Instructor] Let's begin with the context API.
First, we want to create a new context object.
So we do that with this method, which is createContext.
And so, every new context object
comes with one component provider
that we use to share global states across the application.
So let's say one quick example,
createContext that we're going to use
to create a new context objects.
And in this example, we want to share common settings
about this style in order to change the appearance
across the entire application.
And so, every context object comes with one component,
the provider, that will allow to share global states
across the application.
And what we're going to do with this component provider
is to wrap the top level component, so any components,
descending components of this component provider
will have access to the global state.
And so, this component provider
accepts one single prop value
that we're going to use to share global state.
So I'm going to copy these two lines
because we're going to use them in our next example.
Let's go back to our demonstration.
Here I'm going to go ahead and create a new context file
and I'm going to paste these two new lines.
So we're going to make sure that we import first createContext
in order to create a new context object,
so I don't need to have a default value, so I remove that,
and I'm going to simply name this context object Context.
Next, I'm going to create a new component provider
and we're going to need to have access to the children,
I'm going to explain in a moment,
this corresponds to the descending component.
And so, as I was explaining,
every new context object
gives access to the component provider.
There we go.
And so, all the descending components
of this component provider
will have access to the global state
which is going to be shared by this single prop value.
And for now, we're just going to share an empty object.
Next, we're going to export default
so we can import this component provider outside.
Let's go in the entry points of the app,
and we're going to import this one right here
because what we want is to wrap the top level component
with this component provider, like this.
Here we go.
And so, I'm going to make sure that
now the app is up and running
because now I'm going to show you, in our example,
in the browser, I'm going to open the reactive tools.
And now you're going to see that
you have your top level components
and the parent component is this one, the provider,
which is that the top level.
So any component that comes inside, which is nested,
which is the descending component
of this component provider,
will have access to the global state
which is shared by this component provider.
So in this video,
what we did is to create a new context object,
and then a new component provider.
Now the descending component of the provider
can access the values of the context objects
and then we can manage the state globally
with the context API.
So there are five steps to using the react context.
First, we create a context object
using the method createContext
that we do right here at the top.
Then we create a component provider
and we're going to put any value
in this single prop by using the value prop.
And next we're going to wrap the top level component
with this component provider
at the top level of the application tree.
Then we're going to use the context value
in order to share across the application,
so we can be ready to share the global states
across the applications
with every components of the applications.
So this is what we are doing next,
we're going to create global values.